#### Alexander J. Davis

5117 Fallen Leaf Dr.
RIVERVIEW, FL, 33578
813-465-8252
ajdavis24242@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/alexander-davis-3674716a
https://ajdavis2424.github.io/Professional-Portfolio/

#### **Technical Skills**

- Languages:CSS, HTML, JavaScript, React.js
- Databases: MYSQL & NOSQL (MongoDB)
- Tools: Git, Heroku, MYSQL Workbench, Mongo Atlas

## Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in management, employee development, and customer service. Recent graduate of the Full-Stack Boot Camp through Georgia Tech, and earned an MBA from Saint Leo University in 2020. While completing the boot camp I excelled in MERN, SQL & NOSQL, and Javascript projects. I worked in several different groups throughout my bootcamp and was recognized as a proactive, resourceful, and persistent problem-solver. I'm an excellent communicator with effective client relationship-building skills, and enjoy breaking down difficult objects into digestible and easily understandable concepts peers and clients can understand.

## **Projects**

Weather Dashboard

- Dashboard with a search bar that allows the user to input a city, and pull its weather
- Technology used: HTML & CSS, Javascript, OpenWeatherMap API
- GitHub: https://github.com/ajdavis2424/Weather-App
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://ajdavis2424.github.io/Weather-App/">https://ajdavis2424.github.io/Weather-App/</a>

#### GoodMorning App

- This App allows users to receive news stories from their favorite sources, and save them in one location.
- Technology used: HTML & CSS, Javascript
- Front-end styling
- GitHub: https://github.com/strawhat19/GoodMorning
- Project Deployment: https://strawhat19.github.io/GoodMorning/

#### What's-Your-Deal App

- This app allows users to find and save their favorite stocks, as well as pull information on each company selected.
- Technology used: HTML & CSS, Javascript, M.E.R.N Stack, NPM packages
- Role: Front-end styling, connecting and creating Mongo database
- GitHub: https://github.com/strawhat19/Whats-Your-Deal
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://whats-your-deal.herokuapp.com/">https://whats-your-deal.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### TuneTime App

- This App generates playlists based on the duration of a task or upcoming event
- Technology used: HTML & CSS, Javascript, Handlebars, SQL
- Role: Front-End styling, & collaborated to create SQL schema
- GitHub: https://github.com/d4nnyq88/tune-time
- Project Deployment: <a href="https://tune-time.heroku.app.com/">https://tune-time.heroku.app.com/</a>

## Experience

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

#### **Orangetheory Fitness, Tampa** - Coach & Trainer

- Leading and motivating members through their workouts.
- Helping members set and achieve fitness goals.
- Ensure members used correct technique, and offered corrections if they're unable to execute movements.

FEBRUARY 2020 - OCTOBER 2020

#### **AmeriCare**, **Tampa** - Emergency Medical Responder

- Responded to emergency and non-emergency calls and assisted EMT's with efficient and immediate care to the critically ill and injured.
- Transported patients to an appropriate treatment or medical facility.

AUGUST 2013 - JANUARY 2020

### **Saint Leo University, Tampa** - *Graduate Enrollment Counselor*

- Built relationships with students and answered questions regarding degree requirements, enrollment, and admissions.
- Achieved initial contact with prospective students, and continued to counsel them through the entire enrollment process.
- Assisted new teammates with assimilating to the demands of being an admissions counselor, and helped develop programs and tools to develop new counselor self-sufficiency.

# **Education**

JUNE 2021-DECEMBER 2021

Georgia Tech, Atlanta - Full-Stack Coding Bootcamp

JANUARY 2016-DECEMBER 2020

Saint Leo University, Dade City - M.B.A.

JUNE 2006-DECEMBER 2008

**University of Tampa, Tampa** - B.A. Government & World Affairs